# AHSAN KHAN

# SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER

#### PROFILE

With over 8 years in web development, I specialize in modern technologies like React, NextJS, Angular, Node.js,
JavaScript, and TypeScript. My backend experience also includes PHP and SQL. I've led both front-end and back-end projects, enhancing user interfaces and system performance. Additionally, I've migrated legacy JavaScript codebases to TypeScript and built RESTful APIs using Node.js. I thrive in team settings that value open communication, code reviews, and continuous improvement. I'm open to connecting for exciting opportunities and collaborations.

#### CONTACT

+1 (872) 298 - 2691

ahsanmkhan999@gmail.com

ahsanmkhan.vercel.app

linkedin.com/in/ahsankhan99

github.com/ahsankhan98

S45 Gundersen Dr Apt 206 Carol Stream, IL 60188

# SKILLS

JavaScript, React.js, Next.js, Angular, Node.js, HTML5, TypeScript, Jest, REST APIs, GraphQL, NestJS, Nextra, Python (Programming Language), Express.js, Material-UI, Redux.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, NoSQL, DevOps, Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, Webpack, Testing-library, Jenkins, Storybook, Figma (Software), Git, Databases, UI/UX, Test-Driven Development, Communication, Agile Methodologies, Teamwork, Socket Programming, Data Structures, Version Control, Cloudinary, ChromeExtension, Unix/Linux, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Problem Solving, Design System, E-Commerce, Front-End Design, Full-Stack Development, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

#### EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree

### **University of Toledo**

2010-2014

Bachelors in Computer Science

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Senior Software Engineer**

**BayesiaLab** 

September 2024 - Present

- Developed a modern documentation website using Nextra.js with LaTeX support via reactmathjax.
- Used Nodemailer to send automated emails to users applying for license subscriptions and stakeholders.
- Integrated Cloudinary for image and video storage, achieving a 70% cost reduction and improved performance through optimization.
- Worked with Shopify Storefront API to display products from the Shopify store on the web app based on the user's geographic location..
- Integrated HubSpot for automated lead, contact, and deal creation; set up Zapier workflows for email alerts on deal creation or expiry.
- Connected newsletter forms and live chat to HubSpot for real-time support, automatic ticket creation, and contact syncing; enabled e-signature handling with SmartDoc.

# Senior Software Engineer

**Design to RUN** 

May 2023 - August 2024

- Collaborated with Designed to Run, a platform supporting Democratic campaigns and advocacy organizations, to create impactful websites.
- Focused on attracting donors, engaging volunteers, and amplifying campaign efforts.
- Utilized React and Gatsby to optimize website performance and ensure an intuitive user experience for supporters.
- Integrated API-driven workflows to automate complex campaign data processes, reducing manual effort by 50%.
- Developed scalable templates adaptable for multiple campaigns, ensuring the platform met the dynamic needs of political organizations.

## Senior Full Stack Developer

StrainBrain

June 2022 - April 2023

- Developed the Al Budtender, an Al-powered recommendation engine for StrainBrain, a cannabis industry platform.
- Built data pipelines with Node.js & Express.js, improving recommendation accuracy and increasing shopper spending by 23%.
- Developed the Boosts feature, helping brands increase visibility in retail, achieving up to a 12x return on ad spend.
- Designed a secure RESTful API, ensuring seamless retailer-platform communication while maintaining industry compliance.

# **Senior Full Stack Developer**

Catalyte

Oct 2018 - May 2022

- Leveraged React and TypeScript expertise to revamp an employer marketing platform, utilizing GraphQL for efficient data management and improving the overall architecture.
- Led the creation of a scalable design system from scratch using Material UI and modern JavaScript, enhancing UI user-friendliness and long-term maintainability.
- Conducted weekly one-on-one feedback and code reviews focused on React and JavaScript
  best practices, leading to elevated team competence and project quality. Demonstrated
  backend proficiency by using NodeJs, ExpressJs for database troubleshooting and system
  log analysis, resolving complex issues effectively.
- Managed and mentored a dynamic team of developers, overseeing the project life cycle, facilitating continuous learning, and ensuring adherence to best practices in a collaborative environment.

# **Full Stack Developer**

**Bright Development** 

Aug 2016 - Sep 2018

- Utilized React, TypeScript, and Angular for front-end development.
- Implemented robust RESTful APIs with Node.js for seamless server-side connectivity.
- Hosted the application on AWS for scalability and leveraged AWS cloud technologies. Integrated DevOps practices using tools like AWS for a streamlined CI/CD pipeline.
- Managed storage, computation, and database processes throughout the development cycle. Ensured a high-availability architecture on AWS for reliability.